### Contact

shantel\_perkins09@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ shantelperkins (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Healthcare

**CCRN** 

Communication

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

National Institute of Health Stroke Scale (NIHSS)

ACLS (Advance Cardiovascular Life Support)

Basic Life Support (BLS)

**CCRN** 

Learn: Rhythm Adult Online Course for Cardiac Monitoring

#### Honors-Awards

National Society of Collegiate Scholars

Nightingale's Scholarship

Magna Cum Laude

# **Shantel Perkins**

BSN, RN, CCRN, ICU... will help for COVID-19 crisis locally Houston, Texas

# Summary

Along with being a full-time employee at Houston Methodist Hospital as an ICU RN, I'm willing to offer aid to other local hospitals for COVID-19 Crisis if representatives are willing to work around my current work schedule.

Please message me if you are interested in my help or have questions. Thank you... Let's all help make a change!

Compassionate and committed Registered Nurse who thrives to improve quality of life by providing outstanding care and support to diverse patients and their families in acute-patient settings.

Professional Experience (not limited to): Assessment | Med Surgical | Holistic treatments | Keen observation, communication and intervention skills | HIPPA Compliance | Core measures/ Infection Control | Precise charting and documentation | Excellent patient care | Patient-family education | Leadership skills and willingness to learn | Nursing Preceptor | Safe medication administration | Adapt easily to change of environment and work schedule | Computer proficiency | Emergency interventions | Hemodynamic monitoring | Infusion titration of vasopressors, sedatives, and paralytics | Safety Precautions | Central line & Catheter care | IV starts, pushes, & drips | Endotracheal & tracheotomy care, including VAP prevention

Please ask for Resume.

# Experience

Houston Methodist
ICU RN
October 2017 - Present (2 years 8 months)
Page 1 of 3

Houston, Texas Area

Nurse Magnet Status Hospital

Unit: Surgical & Liver Transplant ICU

-Caring for patient population (not limited to): critically ill post-surgical patients; critical pre-liver transplant patients; post-liver, kidney, and/or pancreatic transplant patients; and plastic surgery patients requiring close monitoring in the immediate post-op period

- Treating and monitoring a variety of conditions including pre/post-operative surgery for organ transplants, head trauma, stroke, pneumonia, sepsis, severe acute respiratory distress, CHF, COPD, DKA
- Safely administering medications, including drips (antiarrhythmics, pressers, insulin, lasix, sedatives, paralytics
- Collaborate with other health care personnel in implementing care plans, reporting critical changes, and ensuring positive health outcomes.
- Outstanding interpersonal and communication skills; superior accuracy in patient history, charting, and documentation
- Widely recognized as an excellent caregiver and patient advocate
- -Skills include (not limited to): bedside monitor; hemodynamics; EV 1000/ Vigileo/FloTrac; blood warming; chest tubes; CRRT; monitoring esophageal balloon pressures; bladder pressure monitoring; bladder irrigation

**CCRN** certified

MD Anderson Cancer Center

Registered Nurse

February 2016 - October 2017 (1 year 9 months)

Nurse Magnet Status Hospital

Unit: Hematology/Stem Cell Transplant

--Provide care to critical patients with complex needs including the intense conditioning period and the acute and chronic recovery phase following Stem Cell Transplantation (SCT)

- Nurse-to-patient ratio is 1:3; sometimes 1:1 depending on critical needs
- Mixed cardiac monitoring unit
- Unit accepts any off-service patients (including Med-Surgical related and patients transferred from ICU, as a step-down unit)
- Administers critical medication including drips (heparin, lasix, amiodarone, and inotropic drugs) via CVCs/ PICC lines
- Responds to codes, performing according to ACLS
- Observe behavior and symptoms and report changes to on-call physicians
- Collaborate with other health care personnel in implementing care plans and ensuring positive health outcomes.
- Engage in patient/family education pertaining to diagnose and treatments; provide continual psychosocial support and advocacy.
- Nursing staff of ride-out team during emergency events

Care.com Childcare Provider 2005 - February 2017 (12 years) Houston, Texas Area

While pursing my BSN degree in Nursing School, I've decided to take a professional role as a nanny, babysitter, and caregiver.

- -Assist families with after-school care and activities essential in their daily lives
- -Attend to skin, nail and oral care needs of the patients
- -Checking vital signs and reporting accordingly
- -Being a role model by setting a good example to the children
- -Providing physical stimulation for infants, children, and adults
- -Able to provide care of 4+ children
- -Provide safe transportation

# Education

Chamberlain College of Nursing in Houston, TX Bachelor of Science (BS), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2013 - 2015)

Prairie View A&M University
Registered Nurse · (2009 - 2013)